Guide to the Patricia England fine print collection, 1970s-1980s
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 3: Ephemera D-Z, 1969-1997; (2 boxes)
  - Windhover Press (Box 11, Folder 31)
    2 Publication Announcements (Daily Horoscope; Memoirs of an Ismaric Spear)
  - Windriver Press, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    Publication Announcement (Who Shot the Bear?, 1984)
  - Wood Lea Press (Box 11, Folder 33)
    Publication Announcement (The Wood-engravings of John Nash)
  - Yellow Barn Press, 1986-1988 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    5 publication Announcements (The Old Printing Office; Dress, 1986; Oscar Wilde: A Problem in Biography; William Morris; Late Verses and Earlier, 1988)
  - Yolla Bolly Press, 1983-1987 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    Invitation, Newsletter (Bookfarm, 1985), 7 Publication Announcements (The Daring Young Man on the Flying Trapeze, 1984; California Writers of the Land, 1983; Robinson Jeffers; True Bear Stories, 1985; Where Shall I Take You To: The Love Letters of Una and Robinson Jeffers, 1987; Cawdor, 1983; Flight, 1984)
- Series 4: Pamphlets, Miscellaneous, 1962-1990; (1.5 boxes)
  This series contains a number of pamphlets, including reprints of much older original works (such as William Caxton), as well as invitations to exhibits, bookplates and keepsakes.
  - Two Aspects of Memory: Adams, Frederick B., 1968 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    Pamphlet; Subtitled: A Celebration of Libraries; Smith College Library; Contains 2 Essays ("Collecting for Scholars," Adams, Frederick B., Jr.; "The Task of Recollection,": Piel, Gerard)
  - Appendix to a Report from the Committee Appointed to View the Cottonian Library, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    Pamphlet; Book Arts Press 1981 Reprint of 1732 Original; Foreword by Belanger, Terry
  - Belanger, Terry - Ten Years of the Book Arts Press, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    Pamphlet
  - The Case of Designers, Engravers, Etchers, Etc., 1975 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    Pamphlet; Book Arts Press 1975 Reprint of 1735 Original; Foreword by Belanger, Terry
  - Caxton, William - Scrambled Egges, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 40)
    Pamphlet; Book Arts Press 1976 Reprint of 1490 Original; Foreword by Belanger, Terry
  - Check list of the Incunabula in the William Allan Neilson Library, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 41)
    Pamphlet; Friends of the Smith College Library
  - Cohen, Morton N. - The Search for Rudyard Kipling, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Pamphlet; Syracuse University
  - Flower, Dean - Henry James in Northhampton, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    Pamphlet; Smith College
  - Friedman, Katie - Irises, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    Art Book; Subtitled After Korin, 1658-1716; Friedman, Sarah K.; Hosanna Press; Limited Edition, No. 35 of 75; Signed by Artist; Tissue-wrapped in Japanese Paper Envelope, in Standard Envelope
  - Hale, Nancy - Daughter of the Abolitionists, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Harwell, Richard - The Touchstone, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Kaplan, Justin - Born to Trouble, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    Pamphlet; Subtitled One Hundred Years of Huckleberry Finn; Library of Congress
  - The Landscape Alphabet, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    Pamphlet; Smith College; Contains 2 Essays and Reproductions of Engravings
  - Miers, Earl Schenck - America at Ease, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    Pamphlet; Curtis Paper Company
  - Observations of the Late Dr. Goldsmith, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    Pamphlet; Title Continues: No. 7: Petitions and Papers Relating to the Bill of Booksellers; Book Arts Press 1975 Reprint of 1774 Original; Foreword by Belanger, Terry
  - Pears, Thomas C. - History of Pittsburgh Bibliographies, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    Pamphlet; Thomace C., III
  - Pearson, Norman Holmes - Hawthorne's two 'Engagements', 1963 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Regulations Concerning the Issue of Trade Books: 1828, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    Pamphlet; Book Arts Press 1976 Reprint of 1828 Original
  - Rehberg, Frederick - Emma Hamilton's Attitudes, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    Pamphlet; Houghton Library, Harvard College
  - Rider, Robin, E. - The Show of Science, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    Keepsake, No. 31 in a Series; Friends of the Bancroft Library
  - A Sampler from the Library of Walter and Martha Leuba, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    Exhibition Catalog; University if Pittsburgh
  - Shephard, Yolande - Mallette Dean, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    Keepsake; Title Continues: Artistic Printer, his influence on Napay Valley and California wine labels; Richard A. Gleeson Library
  - Snider, Robert C. - A Catalog of the Robert C. Snider Collection, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    Catalog; Signed by Author
  - Bookplates (Box 12, Folder 18)
    Envelope of Bookplates with names Miller Hunt, Rachel McMasters, Hunt Botanical Library; Single Bookplate reads John Donne Collection of Hamilton Tyler
  - Christmas Cards (Box 12, Folder 19)
    Press-unidentified Chrismas Cards; Names include Allens, Clarks, Riebels, Vincents, Harvey, Cohens
  - Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 20)
    Note and Announcement; References Presses Arion, Black Stone, and Intersection
  - Exhibits and Invitations, 1978-1987 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    Invitations (to Party at "Small Press Traffic" in Honor of a "sombrereptiles" Book, 1984; to Celebration in Honor of Barry Moser Receiving American Book Award, 1983; to Currier Gallery of Art Poster Exhibit, 1985; to Reception at "Susan Caldwell, Inc.," 1983; to Exhibition for the First 10 Years of Moving Parts Press and Greenhouse Review Press, 1987; to an Exhibition of Original Wood Engravings and 49 First Strike Prints with Barry Moser, Glenn Books, 1985; to a Christmas Exhibition of Gifts to the Library at the University of California, Berkeley, 1984; to an Exhibition on Victor Hammer for the Centennial of His Birth, 1982; to an Exhibition of American Book Art from 1980-1983 at the University of Wisconsin Madison, 1983; to an Exhibition of Mr. and Mrs. John S. Mayfield at Georgetown University Library, 1978)
  - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 12, Folder 22)
    Experiment in Type Cast Referencing Ashley Crawford and Paul Duensing; Card for Women's Action for Nuclear Disarmament; Other Printed Material
- Series 5: Oversize, 1979-1989; (1 box)
  This series contains oversized broadsides, advertisements and keepsakes
  - Daniel Boorstins Constitution of the United States, 1987-1988 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    United States Constitution, Preface by Warren Burger, The Arion Press, 1987; Ulysses, with letter from Andrew Hoyem dated May 17, 1988, describing Ulysses by James Joyce and Tristom Shandy by Laurence Sterne.
  - Calendar, 1979 (Box 13)
    Dwyer's Bookstore, Printed at Hamshire Typothetae
  - Broadside (Box 13)
    Small; Image of soldiers and vers "From the old Taver, Grafton, Vermont"
  - Sheet with Franklin Roosevelt Quote (Box 13)
  - Broadside, 1980 (Box 13)
    Poem, "The Trumpet Vine" by Toby Olson; Salient Seedling Press
  - Broadside (Box 13)
    Quotation and Print; Christopher Fry; Charles E. Wadsworth
  - Memorial (Box 13)
    Poem, Horace; "In memory of Robert Hunter Middleton 1898-1985"
  - Advertisement, 1988 (Box 13)
    University of San Francisco; "Form and Beyond: Art and Spirituality in Japan"
  - Advertisement, 1986 (Box 13)
    University of San Francisco; "Victory Through Suffering"
  - Broadside, 1983 (Box 13)
    Book Arts Press; "The book Arts Press Thought for Valentines Day"
  - Broadside-Keepsake, 1983 (Box 13)
    Printed for the Standing Committee on Centers and Regional Associations of the Medieval Academy of America on the Occasion of Their Visit to Bridwell Library, Southern Methodist University
  - Prospectus, with plate, 1985 (Box 13)
    Basilisk Press; The Rhinoceros: A Monograph
  - Advertisement (Box 13)
    "The Four Steps to Perfect Wine Making"; Antique Collectors Club; A book of Bestial Nonsense
  - Advertisement-Announcement (Box 13)
    Exhibit; Dwyer's Gallery; of Moser "drawing and prints for books"
  - Advertisement-Announcement (Box 13)
    Exhibit and Moser Lecture; Watkinson Library (Trinity); Pennyroyal Press books
  - Advertisement-Broadside (Box 13)
    Calligraphy Alphabet; Anne O'Connor; J.P. Dwyer, Bookseller
  - Advertisement-Announcement, 1988 (Box 13)
    2 Copies; Panel; Folger Library; "Collecting the Book: Public and Private Collections"
  - Advertisement-Poster, 1981 (Box 13)
    Bread and Puppet Circus "Our Domestic Resurrections"
  - Broadside-Keepsake (Box 13)
    Poem; "Fanfare for Jane"; "k.w."; Five Trees Press
  - Keepsake, 1987 (Box 13)
    "A Bird's Eye View of the Whittington Press"; Miriam Macgregor; Signed by Macgregor
  - Prespectus, 1981 (Box 13)
    Arif Press; Sappho: Fragmenta Nova; Signed by Kathryn Clark
  - Specimen Sheet, 1948 (Box 13)
    Centaur Type and Atlantic Antique Laid Paper Type; Eastern Corporation
  - Advertisement-Poster (Box 13)
    Printed on Both Sides; "Le Moulin du Verger de Puymoyen"
  - Broadside, 1987 (Box 13)
    2 Copies; Article Extract and Reproduction of Linocut; John R. Smith; Edwards Bawden; Rocket Press
  - Advertisement-Announcement, 1986 (Box 13)
    Barry Moser; Folger Library; "Emily Dickinson, 1830-1886: A Centenary Celebration"; with reproduction of engraving
  - Broadside-Keepsake, 1989 (Box 13)
    Images of Fish with Text; Book Club of Texas; Whitehead and Whitehead (designer); W. Thomas Taylor (printer)
  - Broadside, 1981 (Box 13)
    Poem; "Cracked Open"; Barbara Luck; Charles Aquilina (artist); Meadow Press; Limited Editions, No. 30 of 100, signed by author
  - Broadside-Keepsake, 1988 (Box 13)
    Cowboy Image and Text; Larry McMurtry; "Printed for the First Annual Meeting of the Book Club of Texas"; Wind River Press
  - Announcement (Box 13)
    Image of Lion and Donkey Under a Tree; For a Dance in the Newark School
  - Prospectus, 1982 (Box 13)
    Pennyroyal Press; Through the Looking Glass
  - Sheet (Box 13)
    Printed with Lines, Volor Blocks, Flower; No Text
  - Advertisement (Box 13)
    In Folder; Text on Centaur type; Eastern Corporation; Appears to Relate to Specimen Sheet also in this Portfolio
  - Exhibite Guide Sheet/ Prospectus (Box 13)
    Appears to be an unfolded sheet of 7 printed pages containing an introduction and listing of Barry Moser's illustrations for "The California Danate"; No context givent; May relate to the advertisement-announcement for a Moser exhibit at Dwyer's Gallery also in this portfolio.
  - Broadside-Keepsake, 1983 (Box 13)
    Text on Aristotle Volume; Printed on the Occasion of the Visit of the Umphrey Lee Associates, The Founders' Society, and the President's Council to Bridwell Library; Numbered 183 of 250
  - Print-Advertisment, 1979 (Box 13)
    Text and Image Noted as from Book Lenin's Paintings to appear in 1980; Cloud Marauder-Sombre Reptiles (producer); West Coast Print Center (printer)
  - Poster-Advertisement, 1988 (Box 13)
    Type Image and Text; David Goines (artist); Art Directors and Artists Club of Sacramento
  - Broadside, 1987 (Box 13)
    Poem; "The Blindman"; May Swenson; Pyramid Atlantic Workshop; Edition of 60, Numbered 9 of the 35 Numbered
  - Poster-Prospectus, 1984 (Box 13)
    Arion Press; Self-portrait in a Convex Mirror; With a Letter Describing the Poster and Book Dated January 12, 1984 by Andrew Hoyem